Rudyard Kipling Collection
Rudyard Kipling Collection
- E. W. Martindell collection
  - Writings
    - Collection of 29 uncollected Kipling verses, 1884-1906; typescript copies (Box 16)
      "Ms. Verses to A. E. W.," Feb. 4, 1884
      "The Michigan Twins," Boston Advertiser, Mar. 1889
      "A Nightmare of Names," Civil & Military, Dec. 10. 1886
      "A Picture in Smoke," Pioneer, June 30, 1885
      "Possibilities," Pioneer, July 13, 1885
      "The Rape of the Breeches," Pioneer, Mar. 5, 1889
      "A Rhodian Portrait," 1886
      "Rudyard and Kipling," Boston Advertiser, Mar. 1889
      "Selling the Cross," St. James's Gazette, Feb. 2, 1890
      "Signs," Pioneer, Nov. 11, 1886
      "Silence is, Golden(?)," Pioneer, Aug. 18, 1886
      "The Simla Exodus," Pioneer, Aug. 5, 1886
      "A Soliloquy from the South," Pioneer, Dec. 8, 1886
      "South Africa," The Standard, July 27, 1906
      "Summer Homes for Nursing Sisters," Pioneer, Aug. 1, 1887
  - Memorabilia
    - "Seven Miscellaneous Paragraphs with Ms. Notes by Author, Uncollected, Kipling 1883-4", includes folder with Martindell's history of the clippings (Oversize 4)
- Alan D. Wilson collection
  - Correspondence
    - re: Kipling (Box 16)
    - Ballard, Ellis Ames, 1928-1930 (Box 16)
    - Ballard, Frederick L. Jr. to Robert Dechert, 28 Feb 1964 (Box 16)
    - Carpenter, Mrs. W. M. to Lloyd H. Chandler, 22 Oct 1931 (Box 16)
    - Chandler, Lloyd H. to Ellis Ames Ballard, 1927-1935 (Box 16)
    - Chandler, Lloyd H. and M.E. Walfind [sic; name is actually Walford, Kipling's secretary], 1929 (Box 16)
    - Chandler, Lloyd H. and Alan D. Wilson, 1929-1930 (Box 16)
    - Dunsterville, L.H. to Lloyd H. Chandler, 10 Oct 1930 (Box 16)
    - Kipling, Rudyard to Lloyd H. Chandler, 23 Oct 1930; copy (Box 16)
    - Rudyard Kipling and Alan D. Wilson, 1928-1932; copies (Box 16)
    - Livingston, Flora V. and Alan D. Wilson, 1928-1933 (Box 16)
      See also Correspondence: Livingston, Mrs. Luther S. [Flora V.] and Correspondence: Third party: Livingston, Flora V.
    - Martindell, E.W. to Lloyd H. Chandler, 6 Oct 1930 (Box 16)
    - Martindell, E.W. and Alan D. Wilson, 1928 (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous re Mark Twain (Box 16)
  - Writings
    - "Charles Buford: His Ancestors and Descendants; Together With Excerpts From His Correspondence and An Appeal to the Republican Party of the United States of about 1857 Presumably Drawn up by Him; Together with an Attempted Identification of the Persons Mentioned in These Papers" / unidentified author (Box 16)
    - "A Kipling Problem, 'Three and -- an Extra' or the Story of 'The Light That Failed' " / Lloyd H. Chandler, 1929; typescript (Box 16)
    - "List of Kipling Stories Contained in Magazines (Owned by Ellis Ames Ballard)" / Ellis Ames Ballard, 2 copies (Box 16)
    - "A Summary of the Work of Rudyard Kipling Including Items Ascribed to Him" / compiled by Lloyd H. Chandler, 1930
      - "Introduction" by Ellis Ames Ballard (Box 16)
      - Typescript draft and research notes, 4 folders (Box 16)
      - Typescript draft and research notes, 3 folders (Box 17)
    - "Talk on the Kipling Society in the United States and Upon Mr. Kipling's Works, to be Given at a Meeting of the Kipling Society in London by L. H. Chandler" / Lloyd H. Chandler, June 9, 1931; typed transcript (Box 17)
    - "Three and -- an Extra" / Lloyd H. Chandler, typescript (Box 17)
  - Memorabilia
    - Account book of Helen and Alan D. Wilson, 1898-1920; lists wedding gifts, household furnishings, and books in their library along with estimated prices; history of book noted inside by son-in-law Robert Dechert (Box 17)
    - Dealer catalogues listing Kipling and Twain items, 1929-1932; undated; 4 folders (Box 17)